A Guide to the Executive Papers of Governor David Campbell, 1837-1840
Library of Virginia
- Executive Papers of Governor David Campbell, 1837-1840., Extent: 10 boxes. (Box 1-10)
  Other noteworthy items include: proclamations by the governor & lieutenant governor offering rewards for the apprehension of escaped convicts (1837 Apr. 18, June 10, July 7, Dec. 12; 1838 Apr. 2, June 16, Sept. 6, Dec. 12; 1839 Jan. 5, Mar. 14, Apr. 25, May 1 & 7, Sept. 30, Nov. 15, Dec. 12; 1840 Jan. 20 & 24, & Mar. 4); certificates of election for members of Congress (1837 May 6-9); proceedings of the Board of Directors of the Penitentiary (1837 May 12, Dec. 8); proclamation of Governor Campbell requiring the members of the Senate & House of Delegates to meet at the Capitol on 12 June (1837 May 15); proclamation of Governor Campbell for an election in Buckingham County to fill the vacancy in the House of Delegates occasioned by the resignation of Archibald Austin (1837 May 25); proclamation of Governor Campbell for an election in Jefferson County to fill the vacancy in the House of Delegates occasioned by the resignation of John Davenport (1837 May 26); proclamation of Governor Campbell for an election in Essex County to fill the vacancy in the House of Delegates occasioned by the resignation of Robert M. T. Hunter (1837 May 27); patent of Uri Emmons & Company for a single rail railroad (1837 May 30); proclamation of Governor Campbell for an election in Campbell County to fill the vacancy in the House of Delegates occasioned by the resignation of Robert W. Withers (1837 June 5); proclamation of Governor Campbell directing that the County & Circuit Superior Court of Nansemond be held in the Methodist Episcopal Church due to the destruction of the courthouse by fire (1837 June 8); message of Governor Campbell to the General Assembly re. the suspension of specie payments by the banks & the convening of the Assembly (1837 June 12); bonds of Francis H. Deane as vaccine agent (1837 Nov. 18, 1838 Nov. 22, & 1839 Nov. 20); list of persons received into the Penitentiary & pardoned by the Executive (1838 Jan. 25); report of M. C. Lackland, Superintendent of the Public Warehouse, & S. S. Baxter re. a proposed improvement of the James River Company in front of the Public Warehouse (1838 Jan. 29); proclamation of Governor Campbell for an election to replace John M. Patton in the House of Representatives (1838 Apr. 9); proclamation of Governor Campbell for an election in King George County to fill the vacancy in the House of Delegates occasioned by the resignation of John Hooe (1838 May 14); proclamation of Governor Campbell for an election in Buckingham County to fill the vacancy in the House of Delegates occasioned by the death of Samuel Jones (1838 May 19); advice of the Council to build a gun house in Norfolk suitable to hold four pieces of mounted artillery & four caissons (1838 June 1); advice of the Council re. the application of Capt. Robert W. Bowden, Norfolk Light Artillery Blues, to allow one thousand dollars to build a gun house in Norfolk (1838 June 1); proclamation of Lt. Governor John Rutherfoord for an election in Northampton County to supply the vacancy in the House of Delegates occasioned by the resignation of William S. Savage (1838 July 21); proclamation of Lt. Governor John Rutherfoord declaring that the return of the Exchange Bank of Virginia has been made (1838 Aug. 3); proclamation of Governor Campbell for an election to fill the vacancy in the State Senate occasioned by the resignation of Vespasian Ellis (1838 Dec. 7); proclamation of Governor Campbell for an election in Fauquier County to fill the vacancy in the House of Delegates occasioned by the resignation of Edward C. Marshall (1838 Dec. 17); proclamation of Gov. Campbell requiring the principal assessors to assemble & proceed to the execution of the duties required them by law (1839 Mar. 12); proclamation of Governor Campbell for an election to fill the vacancy in the State Senate occasioned by the resignation of Jacquelin B. Harvie (1839 Apr. 16); proclamation of Lt. Governor Henry L. Hopkins for an election to fill the vacancy in the State Senate occasioned by the resignation of Benjamin H. Smith (1839 Aug. 26); proclamation of Governor Campbell requiring all principal assessors to assemble in Richmond (1839 Oct. 23); proclamation of Governor David Campbell for an election in Essex County to supply the vacancy in the House of Delegates occasioned by the death of George T. Lorimer (1839 Nov. 8); proclamation of Governor Campbell for an election to replace Charles F. Mercer in the House of Representatives (1840 Jan. 1); a resolution of the General Assembly that the Superintendent of Public Edifices be required to examine the chimneys & stoves in the Capitol and examine the papers in the attic story of the Capitol (1840 Mar. 17); and a certificate of qualification of Thomas W. Gilmer as governor (1840 Mar. 31).
  Arranged in chronological order.
  - 1837
    - April
      - 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 16-30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - May
      - 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 16-30 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - June
      - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 11-20 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 21-30 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - July
      - 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - 17-29 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - August
      - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - 11-30 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - September (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - October
      - 1-16 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - 17-31 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - November
      - 1-15 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 16-29 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - December
      - 1-15 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 16-30 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1838
    - January
      - 1-15 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - 16-31 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - February (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - March (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - April
      - 2-13 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - 16-30 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - May
      - 1-15 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - 16-31 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - June
      - 1-11 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - 12-24 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - 25-30 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - July
      - 2-10 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - 11-20 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 21-31 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - August
      - 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 16-30 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - September (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - October (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - November
      - 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - 16-25 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - 26-29 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - December
      - 2-15 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - 16-31 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1839
    - January
      - 1-11 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - 12-31 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - February
      - 1-15 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - 16-28 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - March
      - 1-15 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - 16-30 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - April
      - 3-15 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - 16-30 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - May
      - 1-10 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - 11-30 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - June
      - 3-14 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - 17-30 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - July (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - August (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - September (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - October
      - 1-15 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - 16-30 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - November
      - 1-12 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - 13-23 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - 25-30 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - December
      - 1-15 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - 16-30 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1840
    - January
      - 1-15 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - 16-31 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - February (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - March
      - 2-14 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - 16-31 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Oversized (Clamshell Box)
  - 1837
    - Apr. 5 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Apr. 11 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Aug. 5 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Sept. 2 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Oct. 11 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Oct. 11 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Oct. 12 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 1838
    - Mar. 1 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Oct. 9 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Oct. 17 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Nov. 12 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 1839
    - Mar. 11 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - May 28 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Sept. 4 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Oversized (Newspaper Box)
  - 1837
    - Apr. 11 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - May 30 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - June 4 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - June 5 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - June 13 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - June 20 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - July 12 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - July 20 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Aug. 25 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Sept. 14 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Oct. 7 (Box 10, Folder 10a)
    - Dec. 18 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - 1838
    - Jan. 1 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Jan. 29 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Feb. 16 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - May 21 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - June 7 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - June 25 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - July 5 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Aug. 27 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - 1839
    - Jan. 8 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Feb. 13 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Feb. 16 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Oct. 16 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Dec. 12 (Box 10, Folder 24)